Guide to the Duke Forest Records, 1931-ongoing UA.10.09.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Forest records
1931-ongoing
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke Forest (Durham, N.C.)
UA.10.09.0001
114 Linear Feet
The Duke Forest is more than 7,000 acres of forested land in Durham, Orange, and Alamance counties, managed by Duke University for teaching and research. The Duke Forest records contain a wide variety of materials documenting research projects and forest management.
Access Restrictions
Collection is unprocessed and may require screening, arrangement, and/or rehousing before use.
Provenance
The Duke Forest Records were received by the Duke University Archives as a transfer in 2018.
Arrangement
Collection is arranged by Accession; no additional arrangement has been performed and materials are in order as received from Duke Forest.
Biographical / Historical
The Duke Forest is owned and managed by Duke University. It consists of over 7,000 acres of forested land and open fields in Durham, Orange, and Alamance counties. It has been managed for teaching and research purposes since 1931.
The mission of the Duke Forest is to facilitate research that addresses fundamental and applied questions across a variety of disciplines and to aid in the instruction of all students in their pursuit of knowledge, especially regarding the stewardship of our natural resources.
Management of the Forest is guided by a comprehensive plan that promotes the Forest's academic mission while ensuring the protection of its natural resources. The Duke Forest also provides education and outreach through tours and volunteer events and serves as an outdoor recreation destination for the local community.
Beginning in the mid-1920s, Duke University purchased many small farms and interspersed forestland to buffer and expand the new campus. These tracts, totaling 4,696 acres, became the Duke Forest in 1931 when they were placed under the stewardship of Dr. Clarence Korstian, the first director of the Duke Forest and founding dean of the School of Forestry.
Over the years, largely through the efforts of Dr. Korstian, some of the income derived from the sale of forest products was used to purchase additional land. Today the Duke Forest covers over 7,000 acres of land in 6 divisions and 1 dedicated natural area across 3 North Carolina counties.
Early management objectives of the Duke Forest were designed to complement the School of Forestry's mission to advance graduate forestry education in the southeastern United States. They were: to demonstrate practical and economical techniques for managing timber; to develop an experimental forest for research in the sciences associated with growing timber; and to provide an outdoor laboratory for students of forestry.
As academic uses of the Duke Forest broadened to encompass a variety of disciplines in the natural and environmental sciences, the School of Forestry transitioned into what is now the Nicholas School of the Environment. For both the school and the university, the Duke Forest remains an invaluable asset and premier facility for teaching and research.
Text taken from Duke Forest website homepage, https://dukeforest.duke.edu/, and History page, https://dukeforest.duke.edu/about/history/, both viewed 2018 October 22.
Related Materials
Nicholas School of the Environment Records, Duke University Archives, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Collection Overview
The collection includes maps, aerial photographs of the Forest, notes and correspondence related to research projects, ledgers documenting lumber sales, details of forest plots, information on types of vegetations and tasks performed including thinning, data and statistics, and many other materials.
Conditions Governing Access
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Forests and forestry -- Research -- North Carolina -- Durham; Forest management -- Research -- North Carolina -- Durham; Duke Forest (Durham, N.C.); Nicholas School of the Environment (Duke University) -- History
- Accession UA2018.0036, 1
  - Picture of our old Army Water Trailer (Box 1)
  - Forest Products Revision (Box 1)
  - Dr. Harrars notes and correspondence on revising his forest products and dendrology texts. (Box 1)
  - Georgia Pacific (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and notes re: various physical tests to answer some civil complaint against G.P. (Box 1)
  - Forest Soils Laboratory (Box 1)
  - Plans and correspondence to establish a G.S.L. (Box 1)
  - Livingtson Equipment (Box 1)
  - Southern Pulpwood Conservation Association (Box 1)
  - Southern Pulpwood Conservation Association Training Program general correspondence and correspondence concerning a post-graduate internship program. (Box 1)
  - Southern Pine Association (Box 1)
  - Southern Pine Association: Duke Training Program (Box 1)
  - Southern Furniture Manufacturers' Association (Box 1)
  - General Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Soil Conservation Service: Cooperative Projects (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Public Relations: I & E (Box 1)
  - Letters from sorority sisters and Boy Scouts (Box 1)
  - Forest Protection Course Syllabi/Final Exams (Box 1)
  - Forest Protection Exams (Box 1)
  - Current Items: entered (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and notes with SCS (Box 1)
  - Payroll: Forestry Department (Box 1)
  - Time sheets, 1931 (Box 1)
  - N.C. Agricultural Planning Council (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Soil Site Indices (Box 1)
  - Notes on studies (Box 1)
  - Surveying Instruments (Box 1)
  - Correspondence and brochures (Box 1)
  - Herbarium Collection (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Seed Catalogues: Request for (Box 1)
  - Seed Collection (Box 1)
  - Wood Collection (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Humidity Table: Complete (Box 1)
  - Humidity Table Page 1 (Box 1)
  - Humidity Table Page 2 (Box 1)
  - Humidity Table Page 3 (Box 1)
  - Humidity Table Page 4 (Box 1)
  - Humidity Table Page 5 (Box 1)
  - Tables, several copies; perhaps for a text (Box 1)
  - Part of a Draft of a Text on Nursery Management, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Balances (Box 1)
  - Brochures (Box 1)
  - Various Plots, number and locations (G.E.B.) (Box 1)
  - 3 sections (Box 1)
  - Duke Forest (Box 1)
  - North Carolina: Belmont (Box 1)
  - Eatonton, Georgia (Box 1)
  - Data for studies conducted at these locations (Box 1)
  - Blank PSP Sheets (Box 1)
  - Cleanings: 1) Cleaning Compartment 57 Durham Clearcut Strip (Box 2)
  - Cleanings: 2) Cleaning Compartment 60 Durham (Box 2)
  - Cleanings: 3) Cleaning Compartment 66 Durham (Box 2)
  - Cleanings: 4) Cleaning Compartment 69 Durham (Box 2)
  - Cleanings: 5) Cleaning Compartment 2 New Hope (Korstian), Plantation 2, Stand 6 (Box 2)
  - Cleanings: Release of Loblolly Pine From Overhead Competition (Box 2)
  - Honeysuckle Control: 1) Honeysuckle Eradication (Box 2)
  - Honeysuckle Control: 2) Compartment 1, 2, and 3 Durham Division Duke Forest, Memorandum on Honeysuckle Eradication in Yellow Poplar Plantations (Box 2)
  - Honeysuckle Control: 3) Compartment 18, Durham Division, Stand 9, Honeysuckle Eradication 1949: 1950 (Box 2)
  - Light Intensities: 1) Light Intensity field data collected in June, July, & August 1936, also computations and memorandum of all 1936 data (Box 2)
  - Light Intensities: 2) Light Intensity 5-19-34 original field data 1934-35, 7/20/35-7/21/35 (Box 2)
  - Light Intensities: 3) Light Intensity computations of combined readings of 1934-35-36 Reed (Box 2)
  - Light Intensities: 4) 1937 Light Intensities (Box 2)
  - Pathology: 1) Gypsy Moth Traps (Box 2)
  - Pathology: 2) Pathological Investigations: Duke Forest (Box 2)
  - Pathology: 3) Stump Treatment: Fomes annosus Control (Box 2)
  - Plantation Study: 1) Plantation study Compartment 68 & 70 (Box 2)
  - Plantation Study: 2) Plantation study tabulation of plots (Box 2)
  - Plantation Study: 3) Plantation study maps indicating the location of sample plots (Box 2)
  - Plantation Study: 4) Plantation study soil data (Box 2)
  - Plantation Study: 5) Plantation study measurements 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Plantation Study: 6) Plantation study stand data (Box 2)
  - Planting Experimental: 1) Kinsman Tract experimental planting (Box 2)
  - Planting Experimental: 2) Memoranda on locust improvement Compartment 78, Plantation 44, Durham Division (Box 2)
  - Planting Experimental: 3) Erosion control (Box 2)
  - Pruning: 1) Pruning (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 1) Single Tree and Group Selection (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 2) Establishment of Clear Cut Patches, 9, 10, 11 & 12, Durham Davison, Compartment 56, Stand 2 (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 3) Two-cut shelterwood method in loblolly pine Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 4) 1946: Field Data: Reproduction Study Strip Cutting, Compartment 57 (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 5) Yellow Poplar Reproduction Study: Silvic Class. Stand 34, Compartment 1, Durham Division, Duke Forest (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 6) Compartment 56 (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 7) Compartment 64, Stand 10, Durham Division (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 8) Field Sheets: Pulpwood Cuttings. F.S. plots 13, 14, 15: 1958 Measurements (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 9) Pulpwood Cutting Study Southeastern Forest Expt. Station (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 10) Southeastern Forest Experiment Station Plots (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 11) Southeastern Forest Experiment Station Plots 14A & 14B, Compartment 72, Stand 3, Durham Division, Duke Forest (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 12) Southeastern Forest Experiment Station Plots 15A & 15B, Compartment 65, Stand 7, Durham Davison, Duke Forest (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 13) Southeastern Forest Experiment Station Plots 13A & 13B, Compartment 8, Stand 5, New Hope Creek Division, Duke Forest (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 14) Seed Tree Cut: Sarah Duke Tract, Eno Division (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 15) Selective Cutting Experiment, Compartment 24, Stand 2, New Hope Creek Division (Box 2)
  - Reproduction Cuttings: 16) Selective Cutting Experiment, Korstian Division, Compartment 2, Stand 2 (Box 2)
  - Root Systems: 1) Durham, County: G.E.B. Study (Box 2)
  - Root Systems: 2) R.B. Heberling (Box 2)
  - Root Systems: 3) Pine Regeneration Study: R.A. White (Box 2)
  - Root Systems: 4) Reports by R.A. White (Box 2)
  - Root Systems: 5) G.E.B.: Pine Regeneration (Box 2)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 1) Seed Dissemination 1936, 37, 38, and 39: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 2) Seed Dissemination Experiment Summary 1936: 1942: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 3) Seed Stimulation: M.V.B. (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 4) Seed trap Data Analysis (1937-1938) (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 5) Seed Trap Data Analysis (1938-1939) (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 6) Seed Trap Data Analysis (1941-1942) (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 7) Seed Trap Data Analysis (1940-1941) (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 8) Seed Trap Data Analysis (1939-1940) (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 9) Seed Dissemination 1940: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 10) Seed Dissemination 1942-1943: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 11) Seed Dissemination 1943-1944: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 12) Seed Dissemination 1944-1945: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 13) Seed Dissemination 1945-1946: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 14) Seed Dissemination 1946-1947: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 15) Seed Dissemination 1947-1948: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 16) Seed Dissemination 1948-1949: Compartment 60, Stand 6 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 17) Compartment 60, Stand 6, Durham Division, Duke Forest: Data and maps for seed trap location, Crow's Nest Area (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 18) Yellow Poplar Seed Dissemination Study: Louis W. Powell (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 19) Report on Seed Testing with Tetrazolium Chloride: Johnson Parker's Experiment (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 20) Seed Production Area (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 21) Compartment 72, Durham Division, Stimulation of Seed Production (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 22) Compartment 38, Stand 1, Seed Spotting Experiment (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 23) 1952-55: Stimulation of Cone Production, Stand 2, Compartment 72, Durham Division (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 24) Stimulation of Cone Production, Stand 2, Compartment 72, Durham Division (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 25) 1956-69: Stimulation of Cone Production, Stand 2, Compartment 72, Durham Division (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 26) 1956-59 251-260: Stimulation of Cone Production, Stand 2, Compartment 72, Durham Division (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 27) Seed Dissemination Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 28) Sprouting Study 1939 (Box 3)
  - Seeds and Seeding: 29) Sprouting Study 1940: J.R. Neal Tract (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 1) Compartment 52, Stand 2, Durham Division, Conversion by Scattered Clear Cut Patches (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 2) Compartment 52, Durham Division, Duke Forest, Data for Patch Cuttings on Butcher's Area (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 3) Compartment 72, Stands 11 & 14, Durham Division Conversion Study (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 4) Compartment 39, Stand 4, Durham Division, Report on Conversion from Shortleaf Pine to Loblolly Pine (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 5) Compartment 75, Stand 2, Durham Division, Stand Conversion Study (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 6) Compartment 75, Stand 2, Durham Division, Conversion Study (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 7) Compartment 15, Stand 1, Plot 35: NHC Establishment Reports and Memorandum (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 8) Compartment 15, Stand 2, Plot 37 & Surrounding Area, New Hope Creek Division Improvement Cutting (Box 3)
  - Stand Conversion: 9) Stand Conversion (Box 3)
  - Thinnings: 1) Establishment Report on loblolly pine plot 1, 2, and 3 in cooperation with the Wet Virginia Pulp and Paper Co. in South Carolina (Box 3)
  - Thinnings: 3) Silvicultural Studies: Thinning (Box 3)
  - Thinnings: 4) Thinnings (Box 3)
  - Thinnings: 5) The Thinning of a Loblolly Plantation on the Duke Forest (Box 3)
  - Thinnings: 6) Low Thinning and Improvement Cutting a White Pine Plantation on the Duke Forest (Box 3)
  - Twig and Bud Pruning: 1) Pruning (Box 3)
  - Twig and Bud Pruning: 2) Miscellaneous Holly Cutting Data: Red Bud Seed Collection Data (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 1) Water Quality Study (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 2) Finished Soil, Leaf Moisture Data, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 3) Soil and leaf moisture curves: 1932 and 1933 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 4) Soil, Leaf Moisture Summaries (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 5) Soil, Leaf Moisture, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 6) Soil, Leaf Moisture, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 7) Soil, Leaf Moisture, 1936 (leaf moisture Dec. 1935 and Jan. 1936) (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 8) Soil, Leaf Moisture, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 9) Original Moisture Data, T.P.'s 1933 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 10) Bound Water Data, 1934 D.T.D. (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 11) Bound Water Data, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 12) Bound Water Data, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 13) Height of Water Table, 1937-1938 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 14) 1935 F.P. Data to use in Analysis (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 15) Freezing Point Depression O.P. Finished 1936 (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 17) Bound Water: Heat of Fusion (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 18) Water Relations: Forest Trees (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 19) Physico-chemical Properties Summaries (Box 3)
  - Water Relations: 20) Leaf Moisture, Soil Moisture, and Osmotic Pressure (Box 3)
  - Vouchers: 1) Duke Forest Vouchers (July-September 1931) (Box 3)
  - Vouchers: 2) Duke Forest Vouchers (October-December 1931) (Box 3)
  - Vouchers: 3) Duke Forest Vouchers (January-March 1932) (Box 3)
  - Vouchers: 4) Duke Forest Vouchers (April-June 1934) (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports, 1931; 1954; 1963; 1976-1987 (Box 4)
  - Budget Monthly Statements, 1979-1980; 1981-1987 (Box 4)
  - Budget Preparation, 1979-1982; 1984-1987 (Box 4)
  - Duke Forest Reserve Fund 722-08011, 1980-1987 (Box 4)
  - Duke Forest Reserve Fund 722-08011, before 1980s (Box 4)
  - Duke Forest 152-1000 & 116-1000, 1979-1981 (Box 4)
  - Deposit Vouchers, January-March 1949 (Box 4)
  - Deposit Vouchers, January-March 1945 (Box 4)
  - Deposit Vouchers, January-March 1935 (Box 4)
  - 7 copper photo etchings (Box 5)
  - 1 "Forestry as a Career" plastic stamp (Box 5)
  - Lantern Slide Covers (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous photo albums: old field trips? (Box 5)
  - 42 Negative cases (Box 5)
  - Camera parts to Korstian's camera (Box 5)
  - 2 boxes negative cases (Box 5)
  - Photographic Plate Magazine (Camera part) (Box 5)
  - Lantern Slides, circa 1932 (Box 6)
  - Korstian's camera (Box 6)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: 2 diaphragms, 1 shutter, 1 lens, 1 filter, Miscellaneous camera parts and slides
  - Filing Scheme for Photographs (Box 7)
  - Filing Scheme for Lantern Slides (Box 7)
  - Lantern slide descriptions (Box 7)
  - Pictures of Social Sciences Building (Box 7)
  - Photos from Korstian's Bulletin #8 (Box 7)
  - Brunswick, GA plant (Box 7)
  - Pictures from Nicaragua (Box 7)
  - Class of 1957 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1949 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1948 (Box 7)
  - Class of 1950 (Box 7)
  - WVa Students visiting Duke Forest: 1953 (Box 7)
  - Photos from West Coast Lumberman's Association 1943 (Box 7)
  - Photograph Collection (circa 1942) (Box 7)
  - Gainey Place (Box 7)
  - WL Foushee Place #1, #2 (Box 7)
  - 2321 Erwin Road (Box 7)
  - 2325 Erwin Road (Box 7)
  - Brown House (Box 7)
  - Elmer Burrough's House (Box 7)
  - J.L. Burrough's House (Box 7)
  - Clayton Place (Box 7)
  - J.Q. Davis Place (Box 7)
  - Emma Pickett Place (Box 7)
  - T.E. Rigsbee Place (Box 7)
  - J.H. Sheperd Place #1, #2 (Box 7)
  - Bud Smith Cabin (Box 7)
  - Mal Turner Place (Box 7)
  - Log Cabin (Box 7)
  - Hunt House (Box 7)
  - Fulford Place (Box 7)
  - Overby Street (Box 7)
  - Bessie Paschall Place (Box 7)
  - Duke campus pictures (Box 7)
  - Duke Forest Photos (Box 7)
  - Forestry Equipment: correspondence and photos (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 7)
  - Duke Forest Inventory and Statistical Analysis 1979 (Box 8)
  - Duke Forest Inventory and Statistical Analysis 1980 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Equipment Manuals (Box 8)
  - Budgets and Accounting 1931-1960 (Box 8)
  - Rental Property Accounts 1956-1961 (Box 8)
  - Cordwood Cut 1934-41 (Box 8)
  - Sawtimber Sales 1940-48 (Box 8)
  - Sawtimber Sales 1950-52 (Box 8)
  - Sawtimber Sales 1959-61 (Box 8)
  - Cordwood Hauling Study 1936-37 (Box 8)
  - Pole Cutting Records 1939-43 (Box 8)
  - Pulpwood Sales 1949-60 (Box 8)
  - Cover Type Maps 1952 (Box 8)
  - Payroll Documents 1960-68 (Box 8)
  - Requisition Forms 1965 (Box 8)
  - Equipement Invoices 1932-66 (Box 8)
  - Christmas Tree Sales Invoices 1957-59 (Box 8)
  - Insurance Documents 1932-1948 (Box 8)
  - Annual Expenditures 1966-69 (Box 8)
  - Deposit Vouchers 1967-77 (Box 8)
  - 1990 Duke Forest Recreational Survey (Box 9)
  - Land Resources Committee Letters of Support (Box 9)
  - Financial Statements 1960-61 (Box 10)
  - Income and Expenditures Statements 1962-63 (Box 10)
  - Annual Typed Statements, July 1941-June 1951 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1946-47 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1937-45 (Box 10)
  - Duke Construction Company (Box 10)
  - Duke University Undergraduate Council (Box 10)
  - Fire Claims (Box 10)
  - Employee Performance Reports (Box 10)
  - Plant Permits (Box 10)
  - Pruning: Duke Forest (Box 10)
  - R.F.C. Work (Box 10)
  - J. Southgate and Son (Box 10)
  - Vacate Notices (Box 10)
  - Forest Fund: Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Forest Houses (Box 10)
  - Parker House: Hillsboro (Box 10)
  - Inspection Trip: Duke Forest (Box 10)
  - Howell, Miss Mary: Rent Deductions (Box 10)
  - Parrish, Mrs. Cornelia L.: Rent Deductions (Box 10)
  - Recreational Development (Box 10)
  - Forest Locks and Keys (Box 10)
  - Price Lists (Box 10)
  - Forest Locks and Keys: Letters (Box 10)
  - Compensation Insurance (Box 10)
  - Culverts (Box 10)
  - Catalogues (Box 10)
  - Equipement Catalogues and Prices (Box 10)
  - Homelite: a Division of Textron American, Inc. (Box 10)
  - Power Saw (Box 10)
  - Spray Equipement (Box 10)
  - Log Cabin (Robinson Place) (Box 10)
  - Boy Scout Camp (Box 10)
  - Leases and Agreements (Box 10)
  - Leases and Liens (Box 10)
  - Leases and Liens: Blank (Box 10)
  - Marketing Information (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous 1932-36 (Box 10)
  - Markham, C.B. (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Personnel (Box 10)
  - Statement of the Duke Forest Fund 1963-68 (Box 10)
  - Poplar Sales: Veneer; Cedar (Box 10)
  - Dogwood and Hickory (Box 10)
  - Posts (Box 10)
  - Christmas Tree Accounts (Box 10)
  - Sand and Soil Sales (Box 10)
  - Decorative Material; Ornamental Stock: Miscellaneous (Box 10)
  - Duke Forest Symposium 1971 (Box 10)
  - Duke Forest Directorship Correspondance (Box 10)
  - Vehicles: Blue Goose Retirement Fund (1959 GMV truck) 1982 (Box 10)
  - Tobacco Allotments (Box 10)
  - Fire Control: State (Box 10)
  - Deposit Vouchers, October-December 1932 (Box 10)
  - Deposit Vouchers, January-March 1940 (Box 10)
  - Deposit Vouchers, January-March 1950 (Box 10)
  - Deposit Vouchers, January-March 1960 (Box 10)
  - Minutes of the School of Forestry Faculty Meetings (bound), 1938-1958 (Box 10)
  - Folder 1: Slash Pine Field Records S186-198 (Box 11)
  - Folder 1: Slash Pine Field Records S199, 213-215 (Box 11)
  - Folder 1: Slash Pine Field Records S216-228 (Box 11)
  - Folder 1: Slash Pine Field Records S229-231 (Box 11)
  - Folder 1: Slash Pine Field Records S400-412 (Box 11)
  - Folder 1: Second Report on Timber and Soil Inventory of Caswell Wildlife Management Area, Caswell County, North Carolina, Phase One (by T.S. Coile, Inc.) (Box 11)
  - Folder 2: Caswell County Project: Material from Jim Brown re: old assumptions for F.S. (Box 11)
  - Folder 2: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP1-13 (Box 11)
  - Folder 2: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP14-22 (Box 11)
  - Folder 2: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP32-38 (Box 11)
  - Folder 3: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP39-50 (Box 11)
  - Folder 3: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP51-64 (Box 11)
  - Folder 3: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP65-78 (Box 11)
  - Folder 3: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP79-92 (Box 11)
  - Folder 3: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP93-103 (Box 11)
  - Folder 3: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP104-115 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP116-127 (not including 117: Pond Pine) (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP128-140 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP114-153 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP154-165 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP166-177 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP178-189 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP190-201 (Box 11)
  - Folder 4: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP202-214 (Box 11)
  - Folder 5: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP215-227 (Box 11)
  - Folder 5: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP228-241 (not including CP235: Slash) (Box 11)
  - Folder 5: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP242-254 (Box 11)
  - Folder 5: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP255-267 (Box 11)
  - Folder 5: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP268-280 (Box 11)
  - Folder 5: Loblolly Pine Field Records CP281-291 (Box 11)